Hey guys Shan this side welcome back and
today in consumer Kafka consumer part
what we are going to cover is very
important topic that is exception
handling very favorite topic for the
interview and very confusing topic for
an engineer not from the perspective of
using it very easy to use but by knowing
how exactly it worked internally
yeah because there are lot of things
abstracted to us so I will try to go in
depth as much as possible and let's see
uh if we are able to uncover this
exception handling in Kafa consumer.
So there are two places during which
exception can come in our consumer
application. The first is during des
serialization and second is while
processing the record. So this is one
very high level flow like our consumer
fetch the event from the broker okay and
after let's say it got 200 records now
it performed the d serialize for the
each record okay so this is the first
place where exception can come that you
are not able to des serialize the record
properly okay and this is you can say at
a very popular term you can say in term
of is like poison pill
problem. Poison pill problem means one
bad message
one bad message can
can make your consumer stuck forever.
Okay I will show you how what is this
poison pill problem. The let's say after
the decentralization the next is uh it
invokes your kafka listener where you
process the record. So while process the
record this is the second place where
exception can come null pointer
exception just for that because this is
our business logic and after that we
commit the offset. So this is the only
place where two uh exceptions can come
and we have to handle it so that our
Kafka consumer do not get stuck and
events whichever is failed is properly
stored for the future use so that we can
take action on it.
Got it? So let's first see exception
during deserialization step. So if we
understand this properly exception
during uh dialization step this is using
the same framework itself like the
solution is similar. Okay only you can
say that the place is different but the
solution is same for both the exception
handling exception
handling
whatever the framework we are going to
use that is same for both. Okay. Okay.
So if you understand this, it is also
using the same thing. Nothing different.
Cool.
What is the problem? Dialization step is
infinite loop. And this can happen
because of one bad message or you can
say that one poison pill. So poison pill
when interview say it mean a bad
message.
one bad message and when your consumer
try to desalize it, it can stuck forever
in an infinite loop and even if you stop
it and you run it back again, it will
goes to the infinite loop.
Let's say this flow the producer
publishing the value as a string. Okay,
it goes to the broker and the consumer
but expecting the value as JSON let's
say. So it tried to des serialize this
as a JSON. It tried to convert to an
object. But this is let's say string.
So during des serialization an exception
happens. Okay. Because uh here it is
sending an string hello. But here it is
expecting a JSON like proper JSON format
key value. So decentralization exception
comes. So what generally happened today
is it will print the error stress and
then again goes to the pole. Okay. Now
see what happen is currently let's say
the offset read currently it point to
two means whenever the consumer need to
fetch the next record it will fetch this
offset and this is the offset or or you
can say this is the offset where record
which is present at this offset is the
buggy one.
So now when every time you do the poll
you get this message present at this
offset. So again the decalization
exception happen again you print the
stack trace again pole it goes into
infinite loop because you are not able
to success successfully read this
offset. So commit is not done. So
your consumer goes into infinite loop
and even if you stop it run it and after
when the consumer is up what it will do
it will automatically do poll and while
polling it up it will fetch this record
next record which is again a buggy
message again goes to infinite loop.
Okay let's see the demo first like if
you are able to reproduce this issue. Uh
so this is my producer. So in
application dot uh properties currently
let's say first uh let's see our
producer consumer setup is working
properly or not uh we will send one
write message. So key is string value is
JSON only and order controller when this
API is hit it will send
uh key is a string and order is an
object. So everything is right. So
producer I am starting.
Okay. So producer application started
and consumer is also reading a string
and uh value is JSON properly
and here it's reading this topic
received order event. So let me start
the consumer also very very simple. So
first let's see that everything is
working fine then only we will try to
reproduce it. So I am sending I'm
hitting the event order
let's say 01
order created event publish so it is in
partition zero and it is able to read it
properly and let's see
here in the partition zero
order events partition zero
Okay. 01. So loss is there and also we
will see
we will see the consumer status also
like their offset because uh they should
have read it properly right so I'm just
checking the consumer offset issues. So
just a sec.
So consumer group.
So this is the our consumer group right.
So here let me open the
application.properties
order consumer group we just want to
check its status. So yeah so here if you
see
hm so three partitions we have partition
zero partition one partition two and how
many consumers we have is only one.
Okay. So all three partition is assigned
to consumer one itself. Okay. So that is
fine. And here if you see current offset
partition zero. So our event goes into
partition zero. Right? So current offset
is one. Log offset is one. Log offset
log end offset means one record is
present
overall in this partition. Okay. current
offset denotes like what is the next
partition which consumer has to read.
Okay. So now they are going to expect
one because zero is already readed
successfully. So offset zero is properly
readed successfully. Consumer read the
offset zero successfully. So our
producer and consumer is working fine.
Now let's reproduce this poison pill
problem. So I'm stopping the producer
first. Okay, I'm stopping both. So in
producer what I am doing is
the value now I'm going to send is a
string. Okay, the value now I'm going to
send as a string and here instead of
order object I am sending a string. This
is
not a JSON. Okay, let's start the
producer application. So only one change
I did in the producer is sending a
string value not JSON and what consumer
is expecting consumer is expecting a
value as JSON. So it will try to convert
that string to a JSON des serialization
will fail. Okay, that's our expectation.
Let's see what happened. So now I am
starting the consumer.
Consumer started all good. Now I am
let's say 02 this is the buggy message
which is going to go let's say see
the infinite loop is going on. So this
is the stack trace which is it is
printing and it goes into infinite loop
and here if you check the status.
Okay. So it goes into which partition
two producer it goes into partition two.
Okay. So in partition two here if you
see one event is there. It is not
consumed anything. Lag is one. It is not
consumed. Lag means it is yet to be
consumed.
And our consumer is continuously going
in infinite loop. So I have to stop the
consumer.
Now let's say you have stopped the
consumer. Now when you make it up, I am
making the consumer up again.
It will again goes to infinite loop.
Here if you see it will again goes to
infinite loop. Why? Because it will do
the poll for this partition. What is the
next offset I have to read is zero.
Okay. And here zero is the buggy one. So
partition two, right? Let's see the
partition two.
Order events
hyphen 2 at which broker it is present.
Uh yeah, this is the one. This is not a
JSON, right? So this is the buggy
payload. You can say that value is not a
JSON.
And when it tried to fetch this,
it again goes into infinite loop. So we
have to stop the consumer.
So you got it this infinite loop. And
why this issue is called a issue
happened through a poison pill. And
poison pill means bad message that now
your consumer is stuck forever.
So this locks I have already showed you.
Okay. And this consumer I have already
showed you the demo that uh lag and
everything
and the consumer log also you can see
that uh like decentralization issue and
all like because of which offset reading
and all. Okay. So that is all done. You
I think at this point of time you would
be able to understand
when decentralization exception happens
[snorts] and we are not doing any
exception handling then one bad message
can make our consumer stuck forever.
So what is the solution? Solution is yes
exception handling error handling.
So
see this flow
what
Kafka consumers provide us is that hey
above the d serialization logic create a
wrapper. So I have created a wrapper.
Now everything same decentralization
logic. Now any exception happens any
exception happen what it does is it
catches it catches the exception now.
Okay our wrapper whatever the wrapper is
there it catches the exception and now
it provide one default error handler.
What that error handler does is
currently there is no retry in the
default error handler and it is not
storing in into any DT. DT is your dead
letter topic. So DT is considered as a
topic where all the failed events you
want to store. Okay. So that you can
take any action in the future.
So currently when we add a wrapper any
exception happens a default error
handler is provided to us which has no
retry zero retry no storage into any DT
it just log okay and commit the offset
that's all
okay so
how to add the wrapper is very simple
okay so earlier our key decentralizer
was a string
And the value d serializer was JSON
right in the consumer. Now it's like
kafka.sup support.ializer error handling
dializer both. Okay. Now this is a
wrapper actually this is a wrapper
wrapper above which actual class. So now
we have to provide the actual class.
Okay. Spring dot d serializer dot key
delegate class. So the this key d
serializer right. This is the wrapper
and this is a wrapper above this class
string. So our actual
key dializer is a string dializer and we
have a wrapper this our actual
value delegate class. Our actual value
dializer is JSON but we have created a
wrapper value dializer is error handling
dializer.
So this we have to add in our
application.properties. properties and
when we add this what it does is it
create a wrapper when any exception
happens our default
error handler catches it it just simply
log it and commit the offset it also
commit the offset
now let's see that
okay so
let me stop it
and here
let me
use this itself. Okay. So in the same
everything is same and in the
application.properties.
So what I am doing is my wrapper key D
serializer is error handling D
decentralizer
value D serializer is again an error
handling DLizer but these are just a
wrapper above these key delegate class
which is a string actual and the value
was JSON so this one okay so rest
everything same I'm not changing
anything I have just added this
now let's see What happened? I'm just
thinking any any other change in
producer? No change. Producer is still
sending the buggy code. And uh here
uh consumer I have just added a handler
again. No change. So okay, we are good.
Okay. So let's start the producer again.
Producer is started
and let's start the consumer again. So
when you will start the consumer what's
the behavior we are expecting now see
the behavior I am expecting now is that
there is already if you see this
consumer offset there is already
one event which is in lagging means it
is yet to be consumed
and when you make the consumer up it
will try to consume this. Now we have
error handling. Okay. So
it should be able to resolve it. It
should log it and commit it.
So let's start the consumer application.
Okay. So it should read it automatically
while doing the poll. Yeah. So here if
you see no infinite loop. Okay. And
there is a stack trace printed properly.
And now if we see this again
lag is zero. Okay. So partition two
current offset now increase.
Okay. So it committed the offset itself.
Now there is no lag even though there is
a failure. So it just uh print the stack
trace itself.
Okay.
So this is added
in production.
Yes, we have to log it. That's fine. But
we also have to store the event failed
event somewhere, right? So that it
should not lost. We should never lost
any event on which we haven't perform
any action. Okay. Now with the default
error handler what happen is it log it
print the stack trace and committed the
offset hey I am done now let's say if in
future I have two consu customer comes
up hey what happened to my this request
which was in Kafka now it's gone like
our offset has been increased
okay now I don't know exactly which one
is the failure
okay so one very important thing is that
in production I would say that we should
not rely on like this default behavior
like simply log and skip that's all skip
the event itself
we should be either store the event
which is failed either into DT the dead
letter topic or in DB or you send the
alert whatever you have to do but at
least some action we have to do okay
plus we also need to do the retry
Generally
when we have a des serialization issue
retry do not help.
Retry generally you can say that may be
possible uh if there is a timeout
exception or something but generally
decentralization issues retry do not
help but let's see how we can add a uh
retry plus how we can store the events
into DT or DB or send the alert.
But if you have not understood what
exactly happened after we have added it,
don't worry because we are going one
level deep. Now at this point of time
all we have to understand is that
decentralization if you don't handle it
our consumer can get stuck. We can add a
default error handler. Okay, using this
it will just add a wrapper above
dialization c the exception simply log
it and commit the offset but how it
internally does we going to see that
okay but here if you see very simple we
just added a configuration that's all
all everything is handled by the
framework
so first thing
we need to add a different retry
strategies like we want to add a so
whatever the error handler. Now
we have to add a retry. So here one more
thing is the default one. Let me see the
default one. It might be printing.
Huh. So it uses the default error
handler is using back off fixed back off
interval zero current attemp one max
attemp zero. So max attemp is like how
many retries is allowed. Okay. And uh
interval is like after the delay of
certain time
there should be a delay of certain time
between two retries. You can say that.
So currently it's zero and max attempt
is also zero. No retry. Okay. But if you
want retry also what we have to do is we
have to create this bean ourself.
Whatever the bean it is creating right
default error handler we have to create
that bean ourself. So in the uh class
which is annotated with at the rate
configuration
we have to add this bean. Okay you can
give any method name. Okay the bean
return type should be default error
handler. Now we are creating an object
of it like new default error handler
and what is the back of which we are uh
providing is there are multiple one is
fixed
back off another is exponential backoff
we'll see that so fixed back off I'm
creating a new fixed backoff now I
provided this different value
so what it will do is it will wait for 1
second 1,000 millisecond
before retrying again and how many
retries I am allowing it max two retries
need to be done. So when the first
attempt original attempt fail it will
wait for this much amount of time 1
second after that it will do retry one
if that fail it will wait for 1 second
then two retries are possible right so
that's why retry two if that fail then
only it will stop
then only it will commit the offset and
then goes out
okay similarly if you want different
exponential backup with max retries this
also you can do so here I am creating a
same bean okay uh which is returning
default error handler so I'm creating
new default error handler and now the
backoff object which I'm creating is new
exponential backup with max retries so
here total five retries I wanted 1 2 3 4
5 okay and initial interval initial
interval says that the first retry
happen after this much delay
Okay. And after that back off set
multiplier of two. So let's say first
after 1 second the second retry
into two 2. The third retry is into 2. 2
into 2 4 secondond. Likewise every time
multiply uh multiply the delay by two.
So 4 into 2 8 then 8 into 2 16. So how
much retry possible is overall? Five.
First retry delay is 1 second. After
that always multiply by two and this is
the maximum delay 10 second. So like
multip let's say you have given the max
retry let's say 10. So first time happen
1 then 2 then 4 then 8 then 16. So it
say that hey if you if your delay goes
more than 10 this is the max. So always
use 10 second after that.
Okay, for further retries.
So this is exponential backup which also
you can use.
So retry feature is simple. Okay. Now
retry is also added in our default
handler. But after all the retry is
finished,
what happened? Still it will just simply
log it and commit the offset. But how to
add into DT? How to add it into DB or if
I want I how to send an alert. What to
do that?
There is something called recoverer.
Okay, this is important because this is
where
you can perform
these task.
Okay. So this is the functional
interface consumer record recoverer.
This is the interface. functional
interface which has this method accept
and this two generic objects.
Now it is extended by consumer aware
record recoverer. This is again a
functional interface and you can say
that it has specify
this like this first first parameter
should be consumer record and second
parameter should be exception.
Okay. Now there is one implementation
already provided by the framework dead
letter publishing recoverer.
We don't have to write this class. It is
already present and this implement this
consumer aware record recoverer and you
can say that provide the implementation
for this except. So this except has
consumer record information and
exception information. Remember
when you have to insert the record into
DT or DB or alert when there is any
exception happens in case of dialization
you have bytes
now you're trying to deralize there is
an exception happens correct so you have
you got an exception that's why now
you're trying to insert into DD right so
it has exception
information also It has record also
which are like which topic key value
okay and exception information and all
the logic to insert into DT is present
here itself
we don't have to write anything so DT
implementation is already present but if
you want to different implementation DB
alert we can also write that simply I
will show you how
okay but understand this
this is interface Function interface.
Functional interface which has this
method and this class is already
provided by the framework which
implement this except method and has two
field record exception and it has a
logic to insert record into the DT. I
will show you the logic also.
Now
very very uh like here if you
see that like now we have to add this
dead letter publishing recover into our
error handler. Now how to do that?
Earlier how what we are invoking this
new default error handler and the back
off. Now we will use this method
overrided method already present. So
when we will create an object we will
create like new default error handler
consumer record recoverer. This one
consumer record recover it's a
functional interface. Remember it's a
functional interface. Why I am forcing
here it's a functional interface because
when functional interface are present
you can provide lambda expression.
Okay.
So first is your functional interface
which has one accept method and two
parameters. So this can be also this is
a child of it. So we can provide one
record and exception.
Okay.
And the second is the back off. Now
let's see how we can add failed event to
DT or to DB or an alert.
Let's add DT feature in error handler.
So first thing first the topic in which
topic the failed event should go. We
have to create the topic. So in the at
the rate configuration class I am
creating a bean. We have already seen to
the producer how to create a topic.
Okay. So I am just creating order.
You can give any name of this but here
if you see topic builder dot name
order events DLT
okay dot build. So it will create one
topic order
events
DLT. This naming is important.
Okay. Why it is important? Because I
told you dead letter publishing recover
provide an implementation of this except
okay and it has all the logic to insert
record in DT.
So now if I show you this implementation
of this class
dead letter. So here if you see hyphen
DLT
so how it find out that in which topic
it has to do is like whatever the like
event which got failed it has a topic
right order hyphen events so it just
append this hyphen dt so this topic
should be present okay so this the same
topic should be present then only your
uh publishing into the topic would get
success got it so that's Okay, whatever
the event, whatever the topics already
you have for order order events, I just
added hyphen DLT. Okay, so first thing
is done.
Second thing is now I am just creating a
bean of let's say I am first showing you
DT.
Okay, so this class is already present.
I have I don't have to write it. Now I
want to use it that hey
whenever any failed event come insert
into the dead letter topic and I want I
don't want to write the whole logic okay
by method. So here if you see it has
accept method okay it has accept method
I don't want to write all this logic
like it's already present why I have to
write all this okay so I want to use it
so I'm just what I'm doing is I'm
creating a bean
so dead letter publishing recover that's
the only thing I am doing and here the
Kafka template you know that for
producing any event we need Kafka
template template. So all I am getting
is a Kafka template object and while
creating a object of it new dead letter
publishing recover I just pass a Kafka
template that's all bean is created all
it need is the Kafka template so that it
can publish an event okay so it all we
have to provide this Kafka template
object that's all so that it can publish
the event
and this is the third our default error
handler so in the default error handler
Now which recoverer I want is this dead
dead letter publishing recoverer. So
recover back off if you want.
Okay. So now here if you see
what we have done is we have an error
handler
it will do let's say two times retry. So
first is original attempt
original attempt
then retry one then retry two after if
it is also failed then it will put into
DT
dead letter topic
how
how this is internally working so it's
all done like if you see the code wise
to insert a fail topic into DT is
nothing. It's all done. All we have done
here is we have added this error handler
which creates a wrapper so that it catch
the exception dialization exception.
Okay. And uh when it catch the exception
instead of default error handler I have
created our own error handler now. Okay.
So we have created our own error handler
which has this recoverer and this retry
logic that's all retry will happen after
that the failed event would be inserted
into DT
but since
we have an habit of going one level deep
like how [snorts] this is working like
how it inserted into the DT like what's
the flow so this is my understanding
so when the pole happens
You can say that what information we
have is we have topic partition. We have
raw bytes and the raw raw key bytes, raw
value bytes. Okay. Now I am going really
slow because this is critical. There are
a lot of uh you can say that
brainstorming uh if you go through this
own you might have uh think a lot that
okay there are so many uh you can say
that tradeoffs you [snorts] can say okay
I'll show you uh one very important part
so when you do a poll let's say what you
have is like a topic partition
the key raw bytes and the value robes
for one record which we have to now
deserialize
Now while doing a des serialization
deserialization issue happen.
Okay.
Now what would happen is we have a
wrapper. Our wrapper will catch it. So
now
what it does?
So it does two things. First it create d
serialization exception object.
it create an serialization exception
object which has all the exception
details [snorts] stack trace and
everything. Okay. So if you see
what our dead letter q implement this
accept method the first it need an
exception object. So this need to be
created right. So when our wrapper
which is your error handler right which
we have added in the
application.properties this one
error handling decalizer. So this wrap
it up. So it catch it catches and create
desialization exception object. First
thing is done. Second it create consumer
record object.
Okay. So now consumer record
you know that consumer record has so
many information it can have topic it
can have partition it can have key it
can have value. Okay so topic we have
the information it will set it properly
partition it has the information it will
set it. Now
key and value. So now possible is you
can have a decentralization issue with
key or decelization issue with value. So
whichever with fields you have a issue
that would be null otherwise data would
be set. So example your value des
serialization field. So there was an
issue with the value let's say. So how
your consumer record would look like
here in the value is null because you
have a des serialization issue with
value but key it's properly able to
deralize it. So in the consumer record
key has a proper value but the value is
null and it also have one more
information header. So see dialization
issue could be either with key or value
only two things right. So it has two
header spring decentralization exception
key spring decentralization exception
value. Okay. And here in this header it
put the raw bytes whichever it has an
issue. So it has an issue with the value
right null. So in the header it has a
spring decalization exception value and
the raw bytes.
For example, if you have issue with the
key decentralization for example, then
your value is like proper order object
but key would be null and header would
be spring decelization exception key and
the raw byes of the key. And let's say
if you have decelization issue with both
now you know that value would be null
key would be null and in the header you
would have a spring decelization
exception value also and its value bytes
raw bytes also.
So you got it. So we have created an
exception object. We have created a
consumer record object. So two things we
have created.
Okay. And that's the only two things we
needed. Our
consumer aware record recover functional
interface needed two things consumer
record and exception. So both things our
wrapper has created. Okay. Now what this
wrapper will do? Wrapper will pass this
information to error handler.
Our error handler which we have created
default error handler. Okay. So what
error handler will do is first do retry
if anything. Okay. So if we have
multiple retries, it will perform all
the retries with back off and
everything. And after all the retries
are finished,
we have a recoverer present, right? It
calls the accept method.
Okay, it call the accept method and pass
this record consumer record and the
exception. It has both the information.
Okay. So at this point of time what for
DT
we are using DT recover right? Dead
letter publishing recoverer. So this
implementation of the accept is already
present. It knows how to insert into the
DT. This logic is present.
So it will invoke the accept and when
the dead letter publishing recover
except method is invoked it insert into
the DT topic. Now here if you go little
inside this accept. So see this accept
method is too big. this accept method
and uh if you go inside this and if you
see this accept method if you go keep on
going inside this method it's a big
there are a lot of business logic
because it has to read the value from
the header and all so I tried to
simplify this into this what except
internally doing it so this is the very
critical publish uh new producer record
and after that whatever the producer
record I have got we need to publish it
Okay. So this producer record from the
producer you know uh it takes three
parameter topic
key and the value. So what is the topic?
It create a new producer record. Topic
is from the consumer record.
Get the topic and put hyphen DT. I
already showed you. So this is how it
decide in which topic
DT topic this failed event need to go.
Cool. What should be the key? Now I
showed you various scenario in the
consumer record. In consumer record we
have a key value and header. One for uh
d serialization exception key and
another is uh d serialization exception
value. Okay, des serialization exception
key and value. So if key is null means
there is an issue with the key and you
will have bytes here.
If value is null means you have a
dialization issue with value and then
you will have a bytes here. But if there
is no issue with value let's say for
example then this would not be present
and you would have a proper object here.
The same logic it has done here. So what
it tries to do that if
there is a key present record dot key
present means value present not raw
bytes use it otherwise f the raw bytes
from the header add it.
Similarly for value if consumer record
has the value object use it otherwise f
the raw bytes from the header and then
add the raw bytes.
So this is the thing but we don't have
to write this everything is present. If
you go inside this create producer
record see this this is the logic same
if key not equals to null. Okay, use the
key
and it put it here.
Okay, so this is like you can go through
it but this is what I have simplified
it. Okay, uh understand that
either raw byes would be present if
there is an issue with the key if there
is no issue with the key proper object
would be present. Similarly for the
value
now very important part whenever we do
produce a message from the producer
setup you know that we need to add a
serialization serializer we need a key
serializer we need a value serializer
okay yes we don't have to write this
code okay this whole flow is just for
understanding it is already present
everything okay All we have to do is
create a topic beforehand. That's all
the
dead letter pushing recover because we
have to use a DT. So we have to just
create it object pass the template and
our default handler with the proper
retries and whatever the recover we have
to use. So dead letter publishing
recover object we have to just assign.
So this is something we have to write
and the wrapper where that wrapper goes.
This one this we have to write.
Okay. And everything is done but only
one last piecing is one last missing
piece is that when we have to publish an
event we have to provide a serializer.
So we have to add the serializer. Now
what we have to add?
Now you might be saying hey Shash why
there is like you are thinking too much
like what serializer we have to add a
key value. So from this above code
if you have noticed
that
the value of key and the value during
produce record what it can be key could
be let's say your let's say for value it
could be order object let's say if there
is no issue with the decentralization of
value so it has an order object but if
there is an issue with the decelization
of the value it would be bytes.
Okay. So in this scenario we need to
have a JSON serializer. In this scenario
we need to have a bite serializer.
Now it's a problem right? So this is one
brainstorming part like based on in your
company in your team you can discuss use
case one
value decentralization issue. Okay. So
how our consumer record will look like
key has a proper value but value is null
and in the header d serialization
exception value is raw bytes.
Now the producer record would be this is
our topic order - events DT this is our
topic key would be record from the key
because this is not null and value is
null so it will read from header bytes
in this scenario the serializer we have
to add is the key should be string and
value should be bytes byte array
serializer
then only it will work. Okay, let's
first see this example till now here.
Okay, till now here let's see this.
Let's set up the DLQ.
Okay, so here uh in the consumer
we have a wrapper. Okay, so this is our
key decalizer
and value D serializer. This is are the
wrapper and these are the actual classes
for the key a string and the value is
JSON. Okay. So producer is sending a
string but
consu the producer is sending a string
and consumer try to dialize as JSON. So
dialization at value will fail.
And so this is the scenario right. So
our value will ultimately get null but
key would get proper value and during
this
producing the message.
So topic key would have the proper
string. So in the serializer key
serializer we have a proper string
serializer but the value would be bytes.
So here in the value serializer I have
bytes array serialization.
Okay. So done. Let me start the consumer
application.
Consumer application is started. Okay.
Now let's send one buggy message.
Order - 33. Let's say I send it. Order
created. Event publish. Now let's see
what happened.
So here our consumer application if we
see
h
so no exception at this point of time
right so because now default is not
logging okay now we have used the DT so
this failed event might have reached to
a DT so we can check our DT topic so
here I am checking
broker one logs order events - DT let's
say partition one I'm checking
so oh yeah so there is some records in
the partition one and what it is so here
if you see offset zero
and uh these are headers I told you
right a lot of headers it had I showed
you only two headers for key and for
value it have lot of headers but what is
the payload. This is the test message.
Okay, because
producer is sending a string, consumer
is tried to JSON decelerialize it.
Exception happens and the record goes
into this. Okay, so you can hit another.
Let me hit one more time. Same thing.
Okay, so here now another record might
have come. So this is clear.
Now here if you see another use case
if key decentralization field see why
I'm showing you this two use cases
because there is one hidden gap. Now
what if use case two key dialization
failed. What would our consumer record
value has order object key is now null
and in the header we have a dialization
exception key bytes and what is the
producer record would be look like topic
proper. Now in the key what it should be
key bytes would be there and the value
object would be present. Now will the
same serializer will work? No. Now you
want the key serializer should be bytes
and the value serializer should not be
bite. It should be an object.
So now it should have this uh key should
be bite and the value serializer should
be JSON. So now you might be thinking
right then like uh we can't just change
serializer again and again right like
it's uh challenging and it is also
possible that in many companies keys are
also an object keys are also an object
so it's possible that sometime value
dialization
fails sometime key so you can have all
possibilities so key value so you can
have here let's say now bytes during
this publish record and here you have an
object. Sometime you can have here
object this is bite and sometime both
are bytes
okay now what to do this is challenging
right you can't have one serializer now
for all this case so that's where my
here so see there are again from an
architecture point of view I would say
that the one thing is that hey
do you really have key as an object if
Yes, [snorts] then yes we can discuss
further. But if no key is also an string
then there is a very less chance or you
can say that no chance that there is a
dialization issue with key comes. Okay
then only the value dialization issue
will come and then if it comes then it
can only have a baryialization.
So this will work if your key is a
string let's say but in scenario where
your key is also an object
where your key is also an object then
the safest is that the key serializer
should be bite value serializer should
be bite
that means when we produce the record
our key should always be bytes order
should always be bytes
Okay. So here indirectly if you see the
dead letter publishing recoverer.
Okay. So this is the method
create producer record which actually
does this part. If key not equals to
output key okay which is nothing but a
bytes
otherwise the object you can say.
So we need to change this. we need to
override this create producer record
method and that's what
here I have done that so in consumer
config
okay so here in this one see when
creating a dead letter publishing
recoverer what we generally do is we
create a new object that's all but now I
have also overrided this method
Now I am already making sure that
whenever we are doing producer record we
have a topic partition whatever the key
and value is always should be bytes
only. So I just put this logic.
So key is not equals to null.
Okay, key is not equals to null then I'm
putting a key itself means it's an
already a bytes
because see this method create producer
record it accept byte so means already a
bite otherwise convert it to a bite
similarly
if value
if value not equals to null mean bite is
coming so we have directly used it byte
otherwise convert it to bytes
Okay. Now with this case
we can always use serializer as for the
key is byte serializers.
This byte serializer byte array
serializer
safely. So that's what I showed you
here. So now while creating a dead
letter publishing recover I just
overrided that method and just make sure
that if this key is not null so use this
bytes otherwise whatever the uh from the
record key is coming right it just first
convert it to bytes. Similarly if this
value bytes is not null use this
otherwise record dot get whatever the
value convert it to bytes and then use
it
and that's all. This is the same now you
don't have this issue which serializer
to use again nobody like I don't think
so uh interviewer also will go into this
depth this is only for who are
intensively working in Kafka they might
have stuck to this scenario that this
during error exception this issue can
also come how to handle it
okay now you might be saying that Okay,
now DT is clear,
super clear, right?
And we we don't have to write any code
almost all the logic is present here
from our side mostly is configuration.
This is also I would say that
configuration only.
Now what if you have to insert into DB
not DT? What if you have to send an
alert? Very simple. I startingly itself
told you that the first one itself
consumer record recover is a functional
interface. It can accept lambda
expression. So you can provide your own
implementation. By default there is only
one implementation which is uh for the
dead letter topic.
There is no more implementation but you
can provide lambda expression like your
implementation. So two parameter record
and exception because you know that
error handler invoke the accept method
and pass record and exception. So this
is now you can say that lambda
expression for implementation for the
accept method we are providing and now
if you have to insert NDB you can insert
it. If you have to send an alert here
you can send it. Whatever your business
logic you can add it here. So like this
I am running. So here instead of putting
into DT it's now printing failed record
and the complete record itself.
So des serialization exception
is totally done right. Any doubt in this
one
how the data is inserted into DT I have
also showed you. Okay.
Now what if another thing what if
exception come during processing the
records. So this one delize uh this step
is clear exception but what if while
processing the event after your Kafka
listener is invoked you got some
exception what happened? So today in
this scenario
there is already a default error handler
present. In this case we have to add a
wrapper. Correct.
But now for this [snorts] issue
we don't have to add any wrapper or
something. Default error handler always
present. It catches the exception log it
commit the offset for us. Okay. Now
let's say I'm just saying for example
let's say you are not even handling the
exception at this level. So you don't
have any wrapper serializer okay wrapper
d serializers and you don't have
wrapping your desalization logic and all
it's just like uh you are not even
handling exception at this layer. So now
when the event reach here means d
serialization happened successfully key
and value properly. Now null pointer
exception comes. Is there any chance of
again infinite loop which we saw before?
No. This automatically adds default
error handler for us which log it and
commit the offset for us.
Okay. So it commit it. You can say that
skip it. So our event is lost. Now you
might be thinking hey then how to insert
into DT and all solution is same.
We will write our own default error
handler like how we did it. The same
thing.
The same thing, right?
The same thing. New default error
handler.
You can provide the retry how many times
you want to retry and the recover.
Recoverer could be your DT which you
don't have to write the implementation
or your custom like you can provide like
this the same thing. So the same
solution will work for both.
Okay, same solution work for both. Try
it out. Okay, and any doubt feel free to
comment. Okay, guys. Bye.